Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Sam Liptzin, Mar 22, 1979; cuid1370
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 399)
  - Frank Lovell, Jan 19, 1990; cuid1371
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Lovell 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 312 A-B)
  - Frank Lovell, Feb 2, 1990; cuid1372
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Lovell 4-5)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 313)
  - Luisa, May 3, 1979 and Mar 30, 1979; cuid1373
    Interview documents the activities of the United Electrical Workers Local 431 at the Emerson Electric Company in Jersey City, New Jersey.
    Interview by Ruth Prago.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Luisa 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 148 A-B)
  - James Lustig, Oct 20, 1982; cuid1374
    Lustig discusses the activities of Hungarian-American Left in the fur-leather and electrical workers unions during the 1920s-1940s, his own role in strikes, blacklisting in the 1950s, and work on Henry Wallace's farm. Lustig also discusses his involvement with the publications Uj Elore and Hungarian-American Word during the 1950s-1980s.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Lustig 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 149)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - A.B. Magil, Oct 31, 1980; cuid1375
    Interview covers Magil's in Yiddish culture in Philadelphia, life at the Daily Worker in the 1920s, and self-denial of Yiddish cultural activities for "broader field."
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd A. Magil 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 150A-B)
  - A.B. Magil, Jan 5, 1994 - Mar 27, 1995; cuid1376
    Interview by Allen Thompson.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd A. Magill 3-9)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 332A-F)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Vito Magli, May 15, 1983; cuid1377
    Interviews includes discussion of background as high school supporter of Vito Marcantonio in New York and youth leader of Marcantonio movement. Also covered is Magil's work as editor of Communist Italian-language paper, L'Unita and its support in mining regions and cities during the 1940s-1950s. Additionally, the interview covers Magil's retirement to Florida and reflections.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd V. Magli 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 151 A-B)
  - Mary Magner -- Transcript, Jan 26, 1975; cuid1378 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    Interview covers Magner's activities in the Bridgeport, Connecticut Socialist Party and role as executive secretary to Socialist Mayor Jasper McLevy from 1940-1957.
  - Robin Maisel, Feb 28 and Mar 5, 1975; cuid1379
    Interview covers activities of the Socialist Workers Party during the 1960s-1970s, Maisel's work experience in print shops, and the influence of his parents' radical convictions and activities.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Maisel 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 153A-C)
  - Morty Manford, Aug 6, 1983; cuid1380
    Interview regarding gay rights.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Manford 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 154A-C)
  - Julius Margolin, Dec 30, 1983; cuid1381
    Interview describes Margolin's activities from 1930s-1950s. Topics include the Food Workers Industrial Union, the National Maritime Union, the World War II no-strike pledge, the Communist Party view of Trotskyism, and the Korean War.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Margolin 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 155)
  - Rita Margules, Jun 16, 2011; cuid1382
    Interview by Mike Nash.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Margules 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette Margules 1-2)
  - Alice Marsh, Feb 24, 1982; cuid1383
    Subjects discussed in this interview include the activities of the Socialist Party during the 1930s and the struggle between Communists and Socialists in the Teachers Union.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Marsh 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 156)
  - Anthony Martocchia and Philip Lamantia, Oct 31, 1982; cuid1384
    Interview covers Martocchia's anarchist origins in Italy and his anti-fascist activities in Chicago during the 1920s, the San Francisco/Las Gatos anarchist group during the 1930s-1950s, and his meeting with Philip Lamantia in the 1940s.The recording also covers Lamantia's sense of support from older anarchists in the 1940s and the importance of Malatesta for Martocchia. Anarchist publications in the 1980s are also discussed.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Martocchia and Lamantia 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 157A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Matteotti Club, 1977
    Reunion of Rhode Island activists in Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Campaign, 50 years after execution. Disscussion of defense activities, mostly by Luigi Nardella.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Matteotti 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 158)
  - David Mattis, Dec 28, 1979; cuid1385
    Includes discussion of Jews in film, Yiddish culture, and the Morgen Freiheit and the Forward.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Mattis 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 400)
  - Grace Burnham McDonald, Aug 10, 1973 and Aug 25, 1973; cuid1386
    Interview is part of a series of interviews intended to document the activities of the Worker's Health Bureau, which was founded in 1920.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd McDonald 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 360A-B)
  - Tom McGrath, Mar 9, 1977; cuid1387
    Interview covers literature in the 1930s, poetry and the the Communist Party's Popular Front strategy, and Left Culture during the Cold War.
    Taped responses to written questions from Paul Buhle.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd McGrath 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 168)
  - Tom McGrath, undated; cuid1388
    Recording of McGrath's reminiscences of the Chelsea neighborhood of New York during the 1930s-1940s, including the character of the neighborhood and radicalism there. Personalities discussed include Ray Condon, Mac and Maggie McLain, and Harold Gates. Topics include relationships with various unions in Chelsea neighborhood, waterfront workers and unions (including the National Maritime Union), a local radical newspaper called the Shamrock, McGrath's job with International Labor Defense, and conflicts with the Christian Front and German American Bund. He also speaks about his activities in Los Angeles in the 1950s. The second of the recording part contains additional information McGrath's background, including his introduction to radical left politics and student activism at University of North Dakota and Louisiana State University.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd McGrath 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 345)
  - Ernest Rice McKinney, Feb 25, 1983; cuid1389
    Biographical interview with important African American radical, born in 1886. Topics covered include his youth and education, activities as Socialist during the 1910s, involvement with the Communist Party during the 1920s, his period as a "Musteite" during the 1930s and a "Shachtmanite" during the 1940s, the Unemployed Leagues, and A. Philip Randolph.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd McKinney 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 169)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vida McLevy -- Transcript, Nov 4, 1966; cuid1390 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Topics discussed include the Socialist Party in Bridgeport and the career of her husband Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1933-1957.
  - Medem Jewish Socialist Group/Forum on Jews and the Left, Feb 26, 1982; cuid1391
    Discussion by Paul Buhle and Arthur Liebman on Jews and the Left in the United States from 1890-1982, with questions from audience and response.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Medem 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 159A-B)
  - Sophie Melvin-Gerson -- Transcript, Mar 13, 1976; cuid1289 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    Interview includes description of background and youth in Ukraine, Massachusetts, and New York. It also includes discussion of Gerson's involvement in the Young Communist League and the events of the Passaic and Gastonia textile strikes.
    Interview by Alan Safron.
  - Clarina Michelson, Oct 29, 1979; cuid1392
    Interview documents strikes of department store workers.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Michelson 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 164)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nick Migas, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1393
    Interview covers unionism and politics in Gary, Indiana during the 1930s-1940s, the relationship between ethnicity and race and nationalism, and the Wisconsin National Farmers Union in the 1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Migas 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 160)
  - John Mitchell, Mar 30, 1981; cuid1394
    Interview covers the activities of the Packinghouse Workers and Communist Party in Boston, Massachusetts during the 1940s-1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Mitchell 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 161 A-B)
  - Eva Mizara, Jun 24, 1983; cuid1395
    Access Restrictions
    Interview closed, except with permission of Eva Mizara.
    Interview documents Lithuanian-American radicalism during the 1920s-1960s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Mizara 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 162)
  - Mother Audley Moore, 1972; cuid1396
    Interview documents Moore's youth in New Orleans, the Marcus Garvey movement during the 1920s, the Communist Party in Harlem during the 1930s, and her break with the Communist Party.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Moore 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 163 A-B)
  - Mother Audley Moore, Dec 23, 1981; cuid1397
    Interview documents Moore's experiences in the Communist Party in Harlem during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Moore 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 163)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Anna Morgan, Jan 22, 1981 - Jan 29, 1981; cuid1398
    Morgan discusses her Boston childhood, life in Cuba in 1917, and Chicago in the Depression. She also covers the activities of the Communist Party in Champaign, Illinois, Indianapolis, Indiana, and Columbus, Ohio during the 1930s-1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Morgan 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 165A-D)
  - Gussie Moskowitz, Jun 4, 1976; cuid1399
    Moskowitz discusses her Hungarian-American background, the activities of the furriers union, the Communist Party, and general reflections.
    Interview by Daniel Czitrom.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Moskowitz 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 166)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Elma Munckton, Nov 9, 1983; cuid1400
    Munckton discusses her experiences on a farm in Finland during the 1890s, emigration to the United States, life for domestic workers, and the activities of the Finnish-American Left in Bay Area during the 1920s-1960s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Munckton 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 167)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Emmanuel Muravchik, Dec 6, 1973; cuid1401
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Muravchik 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 337)
  - Jim Murray, Jun 20, 1984; cuid1402
    Discussion regarding Cultural Correspondence.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Murray 1-2)
    - Access Copy
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 335)
  - Rosemarie Muscat, Apr 13, 1980; cuid1403
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Muscat 1)
    - Access Copy
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 170)
  - Lillian N., May 19, 1982; cuid1404
    Interview covers activities at Brooklyn College, in the National Students' League, and with the Medical Bureau of Aid to Spanish Democracy during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Lillian 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 147)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Morris Nadelman, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1405
    Nadelman discusses his Yiddish Anarchist origins in Russia, Yiddish Anarchist activities in Los Angeles from the 1920s-1980s, Rudolf Rocker's personality and his circle, the activities of the Arbeter Ring (Workmens' Circle), and fund-raising for victims of Spanish Civil war.
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Cd Nadelman 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 171A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Luigi Nardella, Mar 1978 and Sep 29, 1982; cuid1406
    The first two disks or tapes are comprised of an oral history interview taken by Paul Buhle on September 29, 1982.
    The third tape or disk is a speech delivered to Rhode Island Labor History Forum at Knight Public Library in Providence regarding unemployed movement in Rhode Island during the 1930s.
    Duration: 116 minutes in three parts; Preservation note: on third part volume is very low
    - Access Copy (Box 20, Audiocassette Nardella 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 172 A-C)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Al Nash, Dec 8, 1983; cuid1407
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nash 1)
  - Steve Nelson, 1981; cuid1408
    Interview covers unemployed activities in Chicago, activities in anthracite coal districts, and the Popular Front and the Spanish Civil War.
    Interview by Rick Wormser.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nelson 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 173A)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 173B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Walter Nelson -- Transcript, Apr 17, 1999; cuid1409 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Interview covers Nelson's family history, education and work, and his involvement in the World Socialist Party (formerly Workers Socialist Party and Socialist Educational Society).
    Interview by Katherine Brucher.
  - Esta Nette, 1978; cuid1410
    One 1978 interview covering the history of the Pioneers, the Young Communist League, and protests.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nette 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Cd 389)
    - Original Video Recording (Box 10, Dvd Nette 1)
  - Demosthenes Nicas, 1986; cuid1413
    Speech on Greek labor and radicalism.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nicas 5-6)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 417)
  - Demosthenes Nicas, circa 1987-1989; cuid1412
    Nicas discusses activities from 1900 through the late 1930s, including the relationship between the CIO and Communist Party in Ohio, newspapers, and the impact of the Hitler-Stalin pact.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nicas 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 416 A-D)
  - Rose Nobel, Feb 28, 1981; cuid1414
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nobel 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 385A-B)
  - Joseph and Ruth Norrick, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1415
    The interview covers origins of radicalism in Indiana coal mining traditions during the 1910s-1920s, Joseph Norrick's role in 1930s-1940s Left, and perspectives on problems of "Americanizing" Communism in the United States. Ruth Norrick discusses her background in Terre Haute, Indiana, meeting with Eugene Debs, literary life in New York during the 1930s, Cold War-era blacklisting from United Nations Children's agency, and her work in journalism.
    Related Archival Materials
    Additional content from Joseph and Ruth Norrick was recorded on the second cassette of the Jose Alvarez interview in the Oral History of the American Left (OH 002).
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Norrick 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 174 A-D)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Clarence Norris, Feb 25, 1981; cuid1416
    Interview documents the Scottsboro Boys case, as recalled by one of nine defendants. Interview also covers the role of International Labor Defense and NAACP and the circumstances of his pardon.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Norris 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 175)
  - Paul Novick, 1979; cuid1417
    Interview includes discussion of the Morgen Freiheit and Yiddish literature.
    Interview by Paul Buhle
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Novick 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 401)
  - Paul Novick, Jan 20, 1983; cuid1418
    Discussion of Yiddish culture and politics including his employment by the Groysser Kundes magazine as a humorist and his involvement with the Morgen Freiheit, which he joined in 1922 and edited from 1939-1988.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Novick 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 176)
  - Paul Novick, Feb 9, 1985; cuid1419
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Novick 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 402)
  - Stanley Nowak, Mar 30, 1983; cuid1420
    Interview documents the Polish-American Left in Detroit during the 1930s, cigar workers, the United Auto Workers, the American Slav Congress, different Polish-American Left organizations from the 1910s-1920s, and Poland in the 1980s. Only third disk of Nowak interview has been transcribed.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Nowak 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 177 A-C)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Marjorie O'Brien, May 7, 1983; cuid1421
    O'Brien discusses her background in Wisconsin, the University of Wisconsin Trotskyist circle, activities in the 1940s, and her attitude towards C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd O'Brien 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 178)
  - Harvey O'Connor, Sep 27, 1977; cuid1422
    Interview documents O'Connor's activities in Seattle around time of 1919 general strike, his work in the Federated Press during the 1920s-40s, relationships with Communists and oldtime labor editors and ethnic radicals such as Ludwig Lore, activities in Pittsburgh during the 1930s, and the attack of the House Un-American Activities Committee during the 1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd O'Connor 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 180A-C)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Edna Ocko, 1981; cuid1423
    Interview analyzes the relationship between the Left and dance in the 1930s-1940s, looking at form and content in radicalism and modern dance.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Ocko 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 181)
  - Hugo Oehler, Jul 6, 1977; cuid1424
    Interview covers Oehler's philosophical background and introduction to Marx, his involvement with the Communist Party, including organization through trade unions and undercover activities within CP on behalf of Trotskyites. Oehler further analyzes the struggles between Stalin and Trotsky supporters and discusses his activities in Spanish Civil War and opinions on French Turn.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Oehler 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 179A-B)
  - Margaret O'Hara, Apr 22, 1980; cuid1425
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd O'Hara 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 81, Audiocassette 380)
  - Gene O'Hare, undated; cuid1426
    Interview by Victoria O'Hare Von Hagen
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd O'Hare 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 182A-B)
  - Bertell Ollman, Nov 5, 1982; cuid1427
    Interview covers Ollman's background in Milwaukee in the 1940s-1950s, radicalism in Madison, Wisconsin, his political activities and intellectual growth in Madison Students League for Industrial Democracy, Students for Democratic Action, and his reflections on the Madison experience.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Ollman 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 349-350)
  - Celia Orlansky, Oct 27, 1981; cuid1428
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Orlansky 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 351-352)
  - Myra Page, 1982; cuid1429
    Myra Page was a Southern writer and novelist who authored The Gathering Storm and Moscow Yankee during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Page 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 183A-B)
  - John Pandera, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1430
    Pandera discusses the Left in the South Slav sections of San Pedro, California during the 1930s-1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Pandera 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 184)
  - Morris Pasternak, Mar 21, 1978; cuid1431
    Interview by Marvin Gettleman.
    - Access Copy (Box 21, Cd Pasternak 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 381)
  - Louise Thompson Patterson, Nov 16, 1981- Nov 30, 1981; cuid1432
    Thompson discusses her youth in Sacramento California, her move to New York City, life in Harlem during the 1920s-1930s, and the Scottsboro case in the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Patterson 1-5)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 185A-E)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Pearl, Feb 22, 1982; cuid1433
    Interview includes a discussion of Pearl's youth, her relationship with her mother, her mother's influence on her outlook, and her Panamanian/West Indian heritage. She also discusses work in a textile factory while at school, and a brief period in domestic work on Park Avenue in New York. Interview includes her philosophies on activism and struggle. She describes becoming an activist during the 1930s and joining the Communist Party. She also discusses Party actions and CP activity within the needle trades union. Pearl analyzes the nature of conflict within Communist Party leadership, particularly with relation to race and gender. She compares the difference between socialist approach and the CP approach. She concludes with thoughts on feminism, critiques of the Soviet Union, and friendship and family in the CP movement.
    Duration: 63 minutes; Preservation Note: One of the audiocassettes could not be digitized due to its condition.
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Pearl 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 296 A-B)
  - Albert Perocco -- Transcript, Jan 19, 1968; cuid1434 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Perocco discusses the Bridgeport, Connecticut Socialist Party and Jasper McLevy as Socialist mayor.
  - Elaine Perry, Mar 26, 1979; cuid1435
    Perry discusses women's role in the electrical industry in New Jersey during World War II and the activities of the National Negro Congress. She also discusses the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE) and the International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers (IUE) and provides general reflections.
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Perry 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 187 A-B)
  - Irja M. Peters, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1436
    Peters describes growing up in Finnish-American left of the 1930s in Mesabi Range, her unhappy marriage to non-Finnish intellectual, and her return to her "roots."
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Peters 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 188A-B)
  - Sam Pevzner, Sep 24, 1978; cuid1437
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Pevzner 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 403)
  - Sam Pevzner, Jun 26, 1983; cuid1438
    Pevzner discusses experiences in the Pennsylvania International Workers Order (IWO), his background as a Jewish entertainer, his political conversion, and activities within the sphere of the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF).
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Pevzner 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 189)
  - Utah Phillips, undated; cuid1439
    Recording of the IWW folk singer recalling experiences from 1940s to 1980s on a WBJC (Baltimore) radio broadcast.
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Phillips 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 190)
  - Marge Piercy, Apr 1979; cuid1440
    - Access Copy (Box 22, Cd Piercy 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 297)
  - Rose Podmaka, Jan 22, 1979 - Mar 19, 1979; cuid1441
    Podmaka discusses her background in coal and steel region of Ohio and West Virginia during the 1930s, experiences at the United Electrical Workers-Hatfield Wire & Cable in New Jersey during the 1940s, and the relationship between the UE and the Association of Catholic Trade Unionists.